{
    "version": 2.0,
    "questions": [{
            "question": "The migrations of particles in the solution are in these three ways, except ______________ ",
            "answers": {
                "a": "Diffusion.",
                "b": "Immigration.",
                "c": "Migration.",
                "d": "Convection."
            },
            "correctAnswer": "b"
        }, {
            "question": "Q2. In DPV, the plot is obtained by plotting:",
            "answers": {
                "a": "Potential difference as a function of current.",
                "b": "Potential difference as a function of time.",
                "c": "Current difference as a function of time.",
                "d": "Current difference as a function of potential."
            },
            "correctAnswer": "d"
        }, {
            "question": "Q3. Which of the following is a disadvantage of dropping the mercury electrode (DME)?",
            "answers": {
                "a": "Applied voltage produces changes in surface tension and hence a change in drop size.",
                "b": "Mercury has a high hydrogen overvoltage.",
                "c": "It provides a smooth, fresh surface for the reaction.",
                "d": "Mercury forms an amalgam with most metals."
            },
            "correctAnswer": "a"
        }, {
            "question": "Q4. Which of the following statement is true?",
            "answers": {
                "a": "A reference electrode is not required for a cell used for a voltammetry experiment.",
                "b": "The diffusion layer is found further away from the surface over time diffusion occurs.",
                "c": "Migration cannot be prevented through the addition of a supporting electrolyte with high ionic strength.",
                "d": "Diffusion of ions near the electrode surface reduces the concentration profile near the electrode over time for the analyte that is consumed in the electrochemical reaction."
            },
            "correctAnswer": "d"
        }, {
            "question": "Q5. In voltammetry, the characteristic current response is generated by applying which of the following signal.",
            "answers": {
                "a": "A variable potential excitation signal.",
                "b": "A variable current excitation signal.",
                "c": "A constant potential excitation signal.",
                "d": "A constant current excitation signal."
            },
            "correctAnswer": "a"
        }, {
            "question": "Q6. The lifetime of a mercury drop of DME during its working should be ___________",
            "answers": {
                "a": "1-15 seconds.",
                "b": "Less than 3 seconds.",
                "c": "3-6 seconds.",
                "d": "More than 30 seconds."
            },
            "correctAnswer": "c"
        }, {
            "question": "Q7. From the following, select the incorrect statement about DPV.",
            "answers": {
                "a": "The height of the peak current is directly proportional to the analyte concentration.",
                "b": "The detection limit lies between 10 <sup>-7</sup> to 10 <sup>-8</sup> M.",
                "c": "It increases the sensitivity of voltammetry.",
                "d": "It decreases the sensitivity of voltammetry."
            },
            "correctAnswer": "D"
        }, {
            "question": "Q8. A half-wave potential is a tool for ____________",
            "answers": {
                "a": "Identification of electroactive species.",
                "b": "Study of the half-life of electroactive species.",
                "c": "Determination of concentration of electroactive species.",
                "d": "Quantitative analysis."
            },
            "correctAnswer": "a"
        }, {
            "question": "Q9. Which of the following electrodes are often used as counter or auxiliary electrode in voltammetry?",
            "answers": {
                "a": "Calomel electrode",
                "b": "Carbon paste",
                "c": "Platinum wire",
                "d": "Mercury thin film"
            },
            "correctAnswer": "c"
        }, {
            "question": "Q10. Which of the following voltammetric techniques enhances the sensitivity through improving the faradaic current?",
            "answers": {
                "a": "Differential pulse voltammetry",
                "b": "Square wave voltammetry",
                "c": "Cyclic voltammetry",
                "d": "Stripping voltammetry"
            },
            "correctAnswer": "b"
        }
    ]
}